507 West 139th Street, New York, 10031

Languages: English & French (US & French Citizenships)

<u>justmckendry@gmail.com</u> www.justinmckendry.com

PROFILE

Data analyst, eCommerce developer and recent graduate, I aim to leverage on my entrepreneurial background and experience in management consulting to help drive businesses front-end operations in the form of data analysis and strategy. I excel in structuring and solving ambiguous problems, extracting insights from quantitative analysis and communicating with senior managers & clients.

- Data analysis and statistical modeling
- Strategy consulting presentation & interpersonal skills
- Off/online merchandising
- Inbound SEA & SEO marketing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Suplay, Co-Founder (Fast Moving Consumer Goods - SaaS B2B2C)

02/2018 - Now

- Developing an auto-checkout bot in order to diminish the acquisition time of goods in shortage online
- Test drive bot development & web scraping for weekly online collection drops, captcha bypass and product pricing

Actility, Freelance Strategy Consultant (*IoT Low Power Wide Area Network leader*)

08/2017 - 09/2017

- Conducted market sizing, automated reporting & B2B SEA, optimized marketplace customer journey & UX
- Consistent 1st search engine result page for EU IoT searches, CTR 2.68% (+12% MoM), +6% conversion (€) in 1 month

Cappemini Consulting, Junior digital consultant (Digital strategy consulting)

01/2017 - 08/2017

- "As is, to be" marketplace assessment & best practices, project scoping, commercial proposals & sales deck preparation
- Data mining & market research on best-in class fintech apps (Alipay, WeChatPay) & programmatic advertising (DMP)
- Creating company's 1st data scraping bootcamp & online merchandiser training (Amazon & Ebay)

Locura, Co-Founder (Retail brand) https://www.locurashop.com/

11/2016 - 03/2018

- Sourcing & merchandising brand on Chinese ecommerce ecosystem (Taobao, 1688.com, Alibaba)
- Managed SEM, import-export, customs, cash model, inventory & data management, pricing set-up, website creation
- Stock-out in 5 months (66K€), advised & trained brand managers (Vilebrequin, Hermes JV, Teqoya...) +21% sales QoQ

Fast up partners, Junior digital consultant & E-commerce brand manager (*Digital strategy consulting*)

05/2016 - 12/2016

- Business audit of retail companies' digital division, lead A/B testing advertising on Facebook for lobbying firm, recommended a radical shift in online merchandising strategy for a pet food leader
- Cold called US online based companies & assisted US & Chinese clients on marketplace deployment & EU sales growth
- Signed & successfully launched 1st US client on Amazon EU (120k/year sales) & PR campaign (avg 3k reactions/publication)

Secrets fine food, Associate (Gourmet retailer - Singapore)

01/2016 -04/2017

- Accounting & financial reporting & forecasting, SKU sourcing, Instagram & Facebook daily animation, in-store sales.
- 4 months break-even, 600k\$/year

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- D2C climate change competition (05/2018): Finding ways to produce and consume gas renewable energy more efficiently
- CFA research challenge (03/2018): Conducting an Equity Research Report for Canada Dollar store leader 2nd Regional
- TMX simulation, Options trading competition (12/2017) 2nd place at HEC
- Project identity", Singapore (06/2016): Research and outreach initiative on national identity in Singapore
- HEC Consulting club, Montréal (12/2015): Managing mandate on continuing vocational training BCG training
- AIESEC Corporate relations Director (05-12/2015): Sales of AIESEC's GIP, signed 2 TNs. Designated best CR member
- Model United Nations (HDBMUN) Co-founder, (01-2015): Raised 35k€, 400 students from 5 countries, Elected MVP

EDUCATION

HEC Montreal, Bachelor in Business Administration (B.B.A)

Graduated April 30th 2018

- Major: Finance (Honors)
- Exchange in Singapore management university (SMU) (Honors)

January 2016 – May 2016

International Baccalaureate (IB) – Economics & Science, Lycée International Honoré de Balzac

June 2013

TOOLS & SKILLS

Bloomberg, Salesforce, Postico, Adobe Suite, Facebook Ad Manager, Alexa, Lengow, Mirakl, Boxshot, Keepa, Junglescout, marvel, real time board, Google Suite (Analytics, Tag Manager, Data Studio,...). HTML, WordPress, Basic Python & SQL knowledge.